A Guide to the Robert Bolling Lambeth papers, 1921-2007
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert Bolling Lambeth papers, 1921-2007
The Library of Virginia
50556
13.95 cu. ft. and 32 boxes
Robert Bolling Lambeth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Elizabeth Lambeth Gereau of Lynchburg.
Biographical Information
Robert Bolling Lambeth was born 1 April 1915 in Bedford County, Virginia, to Samuel Summerfield Lambeth (1871-1945) and Margaret Walker Bolling Lambeth (1881-1966). Lambeth attended Allen's Mountain School in Bedford, Virginia, then St. Christopher's in Richmond, Virginia, and graduated from Randolph-Macon Academy in Bedford. He attended Washington and Lee University and George Washington University. Lambeth graduated from the University of Virginia Law School in 1940. During World War II, he was a naval intelligence officer serving on the staff of General Douglas McArthur. After the war, Lambeth returned to practice law in Bedford, and served as commonwealth's attorney for Bedford County from 1948 to 1961. He was the founder and legal council for Liberty Bank of Bedford, and he was a promoter of the Smith Mountain dam, lake, and park. Lambeth was active in public education and historic preservation. He married Clara Elizabeth Sizemore (1913-2010) 3 October 1942, and they had two children. Lambeth died 17 October 1999 and was buried in Oakwood Cemetery in Bedford.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1921-2007, of Robert Bolling Lambeth (1915-1999) of Bedford County, Virginia, consisting of advertisements, articles, clippings, correspondence, magazines, maps, notes, photographs, reports, speeches, and other papers concerning Lambeth's activities as a member of the Roanoke River Basin Association, as a naval officer during World War II, as an organizer of various festivals, and as a candidate for political office. Papers highlight his interest in education, religion, conservation, law, and finance, among other topics.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Roanoke River Basin Association
Series II: Naval service
Series III: Personal Papers
Series IV: Festivals
Series V: Law, finance, and economics
Series VI: Politics
Series VII: Planning
Series VIII: Education
Series IX: UVA magazines and newsletters
Series X: Chamber of Commerce
Series XI: General publications
Series XII: Advertisements
Series XIII: General subjects
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Robert Bolling Lambeth, Sr., papers, 1922-1952 (LVA accession 51630).
Contents List
- Series I: Roanoke River Basin Association., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 9)
  Ronoake River Basin Association papers contain brochures, clippings, correspondence, maps, pamphlets, photographs, press releases, reports, and other papers concerning the association's activities regarding the development of the Roanoke River basin.
  - Papers, August-September 1946, regarding formation of the association. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Papers, October 1946, regarding formation of the association. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Papers, November-December 1946. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Papers, January 1947. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Papers, February 1947. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Papers, March 1947. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Papers, April 1947. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Papers, May-June 1947. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Papers, July 1947. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Papers, August-September 1947. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Papers, October 1947. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Papers, November-December 1947. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Papers, January 1948. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Papers, February 1948. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Papers, March 1948. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Papers, April-May 1948. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Papers, June 1948. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Papers, July 1948. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Papers, August 1948. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Papers, September-November 1948. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Papers, ca. 1946-1948. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Report of a special committee on articles of association, 8 November 1949. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Papers, 1950. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Papers, 1951-1952. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Papers, 1953-1955. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Papers, 1956-1957. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Papers, March-May 1958. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Papers, June-July, no date 1958. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Papers, 1959-1960. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Papers, 1963-1964. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Papers, 1968-1969, 196[-]. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1974-1975, 1979, ca. 1970s. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Papers, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Papers, January-March 1992. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Papers, April-May 1992. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Papers, June-July 1992. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Papers, August-October 1992. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Papers, 1993-1994. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Papers, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Papers, 1996. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Papers, 1997-1999. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Papers, ca. 1990s. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Papers, 2000-2002. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Papers, no date. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Annual meeting, 1948. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Annual meeting, 1949. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Annual meeting, 1950 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Annual meeting, 1950 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Annual meeting, 1951. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Annual meeting, 1953. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Annual meeting, 1957. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Annual meeting, 1958. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Annual meeting, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Annual meeting, 1960. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Annual meeting, 1961. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual meeting, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Annual meeting, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Annual meeting, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual meeting, 1965. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Annual meeting, 1966. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Annual meeting, 1967. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Annual meeting, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Annual meeting, 1969. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Annual meeting, 1974. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Annual meeting, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Annual meeting, 1995. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Annual meeting, pamphlets and brochures, no date. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Board of directors papers, 1994. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Board of directors papers, 1995. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Board of directors papers, 1997. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Robert Bolling Lambeth ceremony, 1999-2002. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, 1996. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Basin Bulletin newsletters, 1999-2002. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Roanoke River Project and What It Will Mean, April 1947. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Statements and press releases of Eric W. Rodgers, 1949, no date. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Lambeth statement at public meeting, 27 January 1950. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Speeches, 1950. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Roanoke River, Va. and N.C.: Letter from the Secretary of War, 1944. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Roanoke River basin, 1945. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Roanoke River basin report, 1947. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Report of the North Carolina Department of Conservation and Development on the Development of the Roanoke River Basin, 25 October 1948. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Development of the Roanoke River, January 1949. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Reservoirs Regional Planning Commission, 1961-1962. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reservoirs Regional Planning Commission, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reservoirs Regional Planning Commission, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reservoirs Regional Planning Commission, 1965. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reservoirs Regional Planning Commission, no date. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reservoirs Regional Planning Commission--state parks information, 1961-1964. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Outdoor Recreation Study Commission papers, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Outdoor Recreation Study Commission papers, 1965. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Outdoor Recreation Study Commission papers, 1966, no date. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Dam, 1943. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Smith Mountain Lake--genesis, 1944. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Smith Mountain Lake--genesis, 1944. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Dam, 1950. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Dam, 1961. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Dam, 1963-1964. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Smith Mountain Lake, 1965-1966. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Smith Mountain Lake, 1991-1992. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Smith Mountain Lake, undated. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Review Report on Roanoke River, Va.-N.C.: Smith Mountain Reservoir, Va., 1950. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Record of Public Hearing on Smith Mountain Reservoir, Roanoke River Virginia and North Carolina for Flood Control and Other Purposes, 27 January 1950. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - A Regional Park Authority Feasibility Study for the Smith Mountain and Leesville Reservoirs (marked copies). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - A Regional Park Authority Feasibility Study for the Smith Mountain and Leesville Reservoirs (speech copy and unmarked copy). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Smith Mountain Reservoir recreation committee and regional planning commission, 1958-1960. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - /Smith Mountain Reservoir recreation committee and regional planning commission, 1961, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Dam--Appalachian Power Company, 1946, 1958, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ecomomic Impact of Smith Mountain and Leesville Lakes in Appalachian Power Company's Smith Mountain Pumped Storage and Hydro-Electric Development, November 1967. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Report of Field Investigation Potential Park and Recreation Areas Smith Mountain Reservoir, January 1963. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - History of Smith Mountain Lake by Bolling Lambeth. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Drafts of History of Smith Mountain Lake. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Smith Mountain Lake Association papers, 1994-1998. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Philpott Dam report, undated. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Philpott Dam and Reservoir Project, October 1949. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Philpott Dam project papers, 1964, undated. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Buggs Island Dam and Reservoir Project, September 1949. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Buggs Island Sporting and Realty papers, 1951-1952, undated. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - John H. Kerr Dam and Reservoir papers and pamphlets, undated. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Federal Power Commission statement on Power Supply and Requirements, 22 November 1947. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Federal Power Commission: Supplement to the Decision of March 1950 in the Matter of Virginia Electric and Power Company, [1950]. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Application of Old Dominion Electric Cooperative with the Virginia State Corporation Commission--brief, ca. 1950. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Application of Old Dominion Electric Cooperative with the Virginia State Corporation Commission--reply brief, ca. 1950. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Federal Power Commission Decision in the Matter of Virginia Electric and Power Company, ca. 1950. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Federal Power Commission Opinion in the Matter of Virginia Electric and Power Company, 1951. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Supreme Court 97-839--Roanoke River Basin Association v. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, October 1997. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals (District of Columbia) 95-1494 and 95-1500--State of North Carolina and Roanoke River Basin Association v. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission--brief, 1996-1997. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Federal Energy Regulatory Commission--draft of environmental assessment South Hill water supply project, 1996. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fedreal Energy Regulatory Commission, Office of Hydropower Licensing--Draft Environmental Impact Statement Nonproject Use of Project Lands and Water for the City of Virginia Beach Water Supply Project, Brunswick County, Virginia, January 1995. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Virginia County Basic Data, ca. 1945. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Contract for the Preparation of a Comprehensive Plan for the Counties of Bedford, Campbell, Franklin, and Pittsylvania in the State of Virginia, 1962. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Land Use Survey and Analysis: Bedford County, Virginia, ca. 1960s. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bedford County Land Use Survey and Analysis, ca. 1964. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bedford County Sub-Division Ordinance, undated. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Population Report: Bedford County, ca. 1960s. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Bedford County Land Use Plan. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Campbell County Land Use Survey and Analysis, ca. 1964. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Population Report: Campbell County, ca. 1960s. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Frankin County Land Use and Survey Analysis, ca. 1964. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Population Report: Franklin County, ca. 1960s. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pittsylvania County Land Use Survey and Analysis, ca. 1964. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Population Report: Pittsylvania County, ca. 1960s. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Major Storage Reservoirts of Virginia, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Southside Electric Cooperative, 1948. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - News Bulletin: American Watershed Countil, November 1951. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Utilities, 1952-1953, no date. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Water Resources Development by the Corps of Engineers in Virginia, 1955. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Architect-Engineer Experience Data: Lublin, McGaughy and Associates, Architects and Consulting Engineers, 1959. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Housing Sights Years 1980 and 2000: Northern Virginia Region, February 1963. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - ASPO Newsletter, November 1962. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The Care and Sharing of America's Water. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Articles of Association of the Labor Relations Council of Chambers of Commerce. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - A Profitable Boat Manufacturing Opportunity. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - History of the Roanoke River Basin Dams and Lakes by Bolling Lambeth. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Pamphlets and brochures. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Brochure drafts. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Resources for and drafts of Lambeth's brochures. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Maps. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1945-1949. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1950. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1951. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1952. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1953. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, no date, ca. 1950-1953. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, ca. 1965-1967. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, ca. 1990-1995. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1993. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1994-1995, 1997. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, January-April 2000. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, July-November 2000. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 2001. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 2002. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 2007. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, no date. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Newspapers on microfilm references, 1946-1995. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Smith Mountain Lake photographs. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Smith Mountain Lake photographs. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Appearance of Roanoke River Basin Association before the U.S. House photographs. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Photographs. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Photographs. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Photographs. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Stickers, paperweight, and pen. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Series II: Naval Service., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 10-11)
  Naval Service consists of atlases, clippings, correspondence, currency, journals, military records, newsletters, notebooks, photographs, reports, sketches, and other papers documenting Lambeth's service with Naval Intelligence in the Pacific Theater during World War II.
  - U.S. Navy Officer service record, 1943-1954 (folder 1 of 4). (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Navy Officer service record, 1943-1954 (folder 2 of 4). (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Navy Officer service record, 1943-1954 (folder 3 of 4). (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Navy Officer service record, 1943-1954 (folder 4 of 4). (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Personal correspondence, 1944-1945. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Papers, 1941-1942. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Papers, March-April 1943. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Papers, May-July 1943. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Papers, August 1943. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Papers, October-November 1943. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Papers, 1944. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Papers, January-April 1945. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Papers, May-August 1945. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Papers, ca. 1941-1945. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Papers, 1946, 1949-1950, 1991, and undated. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Journals, ca. 1944. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Notebook and clippings, 1944-1945. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Sketches. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1944, undated. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, ca. 1944. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Photographs, New Guinea, October 1944. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Photographs, Philippines, 1944. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, 1945. (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Papers relating to Naval Intelligence, commerce and customs, ca. 1941-1942. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Naval Intelligence service, Fifth Naval District, continuing order No. 1, 17 April 1942. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Headquarters, Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office, 30 June 1942. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Headquarters, Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office, 30 September 1942. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Headquarters, Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office papers, 1942. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Headquarters, Fifth Naval District, Naval Operating Base, 1942-1943. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office, Section B-3, 1 January 1943. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Headquarters, Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office, 28 February 1943. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Headquarters, Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office, 31 March 1943. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Headquarters, Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office, 30 June 1943. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Fifth Naval District, District Intelligence Office, Section B-3, undated. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Naval Intelligence Division, undated. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Douglas MacArthur proclamations and correspondence. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Free Philippines, 17 December 1944. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Kwajalein Daily News, 14 February 1945. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Philippines currency issued by Japan. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Global Atlas of the World at War. (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Series III: Personal Papers., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 11-15)
  Personal papers contains announcements, articles, booklets, books, bulletins, bylaws, clippings, correspondence, financial records, lists, magazines, notes, photographs, poems, reports, sermons, speeches, and other papers regarding Lambeth's candidacy for the general assembly, his church leadership, and his personal activities. Papers include speeches to organizations on various topics, as well as local histories of Albemarle and Bedford Counties.
  - Loyalty Sunday, 26 May 1957 (including remarks). (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Business of the Church (Methodist). (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Materialism and the spiritual. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Sermons and prayers. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Remarks and addresses on various church topics. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Addresses--Main Street Methodist Church Men's Club, 1964, 1966, 1974. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Addresses concerning church laymen. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous notes for church talks. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Sunday School--Genesis and Exodus, 1966, 1969, 1982. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Sunday School--Old Testament history and prophets, 1958, 1965-1966, undated. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Sunday School--Gospels, 1958, undated. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Sunday School--Acts and Pauline epistles, 1957, 1966-1967, 1983, undated. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Sunday School--non-Pauline epistles and Revelation, undated. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sunday School--general topics, undated. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Raymond Fosdick article and letter, 1956-1957. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Methodist Church--Lynchburg District papers, 1957, undated. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Main Street Methodist Church (Bedford) bulletins, 1952-1977, undated. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Church bulletins (various churches), 1945-1984. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Adult Student and Adult Teacher, June 1965. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Can We Break Bread Together? by Chauncey J. Varner, 1965. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Membership Manual of the Methodist Church for Young People and Adulsts, 1960. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - The Methodist Primer by Charles Claude Selecman. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Seven Words of Christian Change by Robert M. Temple, Jr., 1974. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Under Orders: The Churches and Public Affairs by Roswell P. Barnes, 1961. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Wesley, April-May-June 1964, June-July-August 1965. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Printed religious and church materials. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (religious), 1968-1969. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets and notes for United Nations Day, 24 October 1961. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - United Nations talk to the DAR, 15 January 1962. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - United Nations Flag Day program. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - United Nations material. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Speeches at Randolph-Macon Academy, ca. early 1930s, ca. 1986. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - The Challenge to My Generation--University of Virginia Law School, 11 July 1938. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - The Small Liberal Arts College, 1968. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Press Association, 12 June 1965. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Achievement in Faith--Dedication of the Bedford Armory, 16 June 1957. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Koinonia Foundation, 1954. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Dedication of Radio Station WBLT, 4 March 1950. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Memorial Day addresses, 1951, 1953, undated. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Veterans Day addresses, 1964, 1969, undated. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Addresses to the Boy Scouts, 1969, 1971. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Addresses to Chambers of Commerce and Junior Chambers of Commerce, 1950, 1953, 1969. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Civil War addresses, 1960, 1965, undated. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Addresses to the DAR, 1954, 1959. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Addresses on law and legal matters, 1958, 1959, undated. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Addresses on politics, foreign policy, and civics, 1960, ca. 1968, undated. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Addresses to various organizations, 1957-1974. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Addresses on various topics. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - School talks, 1961, 1963, 1972, undated. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Evaluation of Our Bedford Public Schools, 9 May 1967. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Speaker introduction notes. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1949-1965. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Speeches--miscellaneous papers. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - General printed materials for speeches and talks. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Politics, 1937, 1951-1953, 1972, undated. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - A. Willis Robertson speeches, 1962-1964. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Democratic primary--Bolling Lambeth campaign materials, 1965. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Democratic primary--notes on Lambeth radio spots, 1965. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Democratic primary--radio address by William W. Berry, M. E. Padgett, Jr., and DuVal Radford, 1965. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Democratic primary--notes, 1965. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Democratic primary--Lacy Putney papers, 1965. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Democratic primary--poll tax payment list, 1965. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Virgil H. Goode keynote address to the State Convention of Young Democratic Clubs of Virginia, 25 March 1972. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, apportionment, ca. 1940-1941. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Clippings 1941 Governor's race, ca. 1940-1941. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, poll tax, ca. 1940-1941. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, Virginia politics and government, ca. 1940-1941. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - The Case against Nixon by Morris H. Rubin, The Progressive, 1960. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Papers, 1940, 1949-1958. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Papers, 1962-1966. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Papers, 1983, 1989. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Papers, undated. (Box 14, Folder 23)